People always ask me, "Tyrone,
how do you change a bloody tire?" I don't
know.
My name's not Tyrone, and that
is not my car.
Now,
if you haven't been on social media long
enough to see that used as a hook in
content,
I don't know what you're doing with your
time.
But the reason I'd start a video with
that is it's a proven, tried,
and tested way
of engaging people in content.
There's the inquisition. What's going on?
Why is he wearing a hard hat,
and why did he just call himself Tyrone?
And the answer is I said, "Declan,
give me the name of a Black person." He
said,
"Tyrone." I said,
"Excellent choice." Because eventually,
we're going to want to
get into the body of our content,
whether you're talking about fitness,
accountancy, or whether
or not an infrared sauna has any health
benefits.
But if you just start your content,
it's a little bit boring.
And it's actually in this first part of
the reel that people are going to make a
decision whether they leave or not.
Think of it this way.
When you're swiping on Hinge or Tinder
or Grindr, people
need to be stopped in their tracks.
Why are you swiping yes to everything,
James?
Old habits die hard. So you're there,
and you're not really giving people
anything
more than half a second.
That's the exact same thing people do in
content.
However, if you choose a hook
or something that's engaging and
funny, even if you know what it is
and you've seen it before,
you're more inclined
to give that person an opportunity to say,
"Go on then." And it's once that person
stops on your profile,
they'll maybe give you the time of day to
decide whether or
not you get the swipe or not.
And sometimes having a hook,
putting a smile on
someone's face, because remember,
the majority of people coming to social
media
aren't just coming for information.
They're coming for fun, for entertainment.
Even this video,
even though I'm trying to sell to you,
let's make this fun.
Let's make it enjoyable. Education,
banter. Ooh.
So sometimes before getting to the body of
the reel, you can use a viral hook.
You can see what's working for other
people, and you can emulate it.
No one owns that hook, and
if it means more people can enjoy the body
of your
content,
that's only going to equate to more people
being interested in whatever it
is you're pushing. Not all the time,
but sometimes you will have to use tactics
from other creators so you can get more
people to look at the body of the content,
so more people can listen to your call to
action.
If you recreate someone's viral hook,
what are they going to do? Call the cops?
They stole it from someone else in the
first place, too. Try it out.
Maybe it benefits your business,
maybe it doesn't. Do I look like a Tyrone?
Oi.
What?
I thought you said he
was a getaway driver.
What the fuck can he get away from, eh?